Arnab Mukherjee

Undergraduate CSE Student

mukherjeearnab.github.io

☑ mukherjeearnab.arc@gmail.com

• @mukherjeearnab

ABOUT ME

Hi, I'm Arnab Mukherjee. I'm currently pursuing B.Tech Computer Science & Engineering at RCC Institute of Information Technology. My interests lie in Blockchain technology, Machine Learning and Web Development. I have experience working with LAMP and MERN stack, Hyperledger Fabric and Ethereum. My other interests include exploring and solving machine learning problems. I also enjoy designing and developing various frontends. Besides these, I love playing the guitar and piano and sometimes arrange pieces for them.

EDUCATION

RCC Institute Of Information Technology

Expected Graduation: June 2022

B. Tech. in Computer Science & Engineering

GPA: 8.6/10.0

Kendriya Vidyalaya Ballygunge

Kolkata, India

Kolkata, India

Higher Secondary Education (PCM+CS)

May 2015 - March 2018

Percentage: 82.6%

EXPERIENCE

Indian Institute of Technology Patna

Patna, India

Research Intern

May 2020 - July 2020

- Designed and developed two proposals for Smart Policing and Online Transportation services, leveraging the power of Blockchain technology.
- Implemented prototypes on the Hyperledger Fabric Blockchain platform, along with Rest API middle-wares, and React JS frontends.

Insolva Solutions Inc.

Kolkata India

Web Development Intern

February 2020 - April 2020

 Designed and Developed a website for an NGO using the LAMP stack, including the integration of a payment gateway for donations and creating and managing blog posts on the website.

PUBLICATIONS

An Integrated Platform for Vehicle-Related Services and Records Management using Blockchain Technology

Arnab Mukherjee, Raju Halder

- o Proc. of the 13th Asian Conference on Intelligent Information and Database Systems (ACIIDS '21), Pages 337-351.
- o Phuket, Thailand, 7-10 April 2021. Springer CCIS 1371.

PoliceChain: Blockchain-Based Smart Policing System for Smart Cities

Arnab Mukherjee, Raju Halder

- o Proc. of the 13th International Conference on Security of Information and Networks (SIN '20), Pages 1-5.
- o Istanbul, Turkey, 4-6 Nov 2020. ACM Press.

Blockchain-Based Smart Policing System

qithub.com/mukherjeearnab/policinq-network

- o A working prototype of (PoliceChain).
- Implemented on Hyperledger Fabric, along with smart-contracts written in GoLang and middle-ware implemented on Node.JS, this project was part of my work at IIT Patna during my internship in May of 2020.

CaffeineW

github.com/mukherjeearnab/CaffeineW

o A Caffeine like app for Windows.

React JS Frontend for PoliceChain

github.com/mukherjeearnab/policing-network-front end

 The React JS frontend for project PoliceChain. Used Material UI as the UI framework, along with Axios for API integration.

MIDI music generation using LSTM

qithub.com/mukherjeearnab/lstm-music

 This project aims to train an LSTM model on a dataset of MIDI files and then generate MIDI files using the trained LSTM model. The project was implemented on Tensorflow.

Gesture Controlled Robot Car

github.com/mukherjeearnab/gesturecontrolrobot

 A gesture controlled robot car implemented on the Arduino platform, using the MPU6050 gyroscope sensor and RF24L01 radio module to wirelessly control the car, based on the articulation of the the gyroscope sensor.

ColorDropX

github.com/mukherjeearnab/colordropx

o A cross-platform color picker tool built on the Qt platform, supporting Linux, Windows and MacOS.

Periodica 12

github.com/mukherjeearnab/periodica12

 A Periodic Table app built on C#, which provides over 50 different fields of information on elements of the Periodic Table. This is the GUI implementation of my first project 'periodica' after learning to code for the first time, originally build on C++.

SKILLS

- Web Development: HTML5 with CSS3, Javascript, Node.JS, PHP, React JS, Bootstrap 4.
- o **Software Development:** Java, C++, C#, Python, Android, GoLang.
- o Machine Learning Libraries: Scikit Learn, Tensorflow.
- o Blockchain Technologies: Ethereum, Hyperledger Fabric, Solidity, Hyperledger Caliper, Mythril.
- o Database Systems: MongoDB, MySQL.
- o Misc. Technologies & Tools: Linux, Git, Arduino, Docker.